The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Ceng Niu ?
Brother Wang !
Wang Lin,
long time no see.
I see your cultivation has improved greatly.
It has yet to match my handsomeness...
I will let you borrow
that straw hat for a while longer.
There are still 99 wood carvings left.
Don’t forget them when you reach Soul Formation !
Here are the carvings of Senior
I promised to give you.
I want to thank you
for your past guidance.
Now, I just want to reclaim my soul strand,
nothing more.
Yunque Zi, an Ascendant cultivator, entered the Suzaku Tomb.
That means something else is happening here.
I must reclaim my soul strand
and avoid getting involved.
Wang Lin...
You ruined my domain
so I will kill you !
I have faced countless enemies before,
but this kind of gaze that can make my heart tremble
can only mean one person.
Tu Si’s demon...
Tuo Sen
Once I leave this place,
even if you flee to the ends of the cosmos,
I’ll capture and refine you !
He should’ve attacked me on sight
to seize the memory inheritance.
But he hasn’t attacked yet...
Instead, he entered the Suzaku Tomb.
Does he also seek the Cultivation Planet Crystal ?
His cultivation likely surpasses Soul Transformation.
The only person that can face him here
is Yunque Zi.
The aura of an Ancient God ?
So it’s on him.
Look !
What’s happening ?
What’s going on ?
The mountain is crumbling !
The gate...
The gate has opened !
Break !
Attack together,
we will open the mountain gate !
Golden Sea\NSuzaku Tomb
As Situ said,
that must be Ye Wuyou’s tomb.
But entering it
definitely won’t be easy.
A defensive restriction ?
Condense !
With Tuo Sen’s power,
the puppet's cultivation
has indeed reached Ascendant.
Thank you Brother Wang.
Zi Xin and I planned to use the Water Escape Technique to sneak in
but it’s impossible...
This golden-armored giant
doesn’t attack to kill.
To enter Ye Wuyou’s tomb,
you just need to withstand one strike
But this sword’s power...
Fellow cultivator Ceng Niu,
I'm sure you realized
that this strike is Ascendant-level.
None of us can withstand it.
Rather than wait for death here,
let the three of us join forces to resist it.
Brother Wang,
be careful.
Alright.
Very well.
Fellow cultivator Ceng,
the both of us will face the sword first,
then my Junior Sister will take over.
What do you think ?
Don't trouble yourself,
I will face the sword first
and then you two take over.
Ceng Niu is only Early stage Soul Transformation yet is so presumptuous.
He must be relying on that Soul Flag again.
If I can get my hands on it...
Fellow cultivator Ceng, don’t panic !
Qian Feng is here !
Ceng Niu,
prepare to die !
Asc...
Ascendant ?
This is bad !
Retreat !
Passage of time.
Wang Lin !
Ceng Niu !
This must be the statue of the first Suzaku, Ye Wuyou.
That light...
Could it be the Cultivation Planet Crystal ?
However...
Where’s Yunque Zi ?
Wang Lin...
It’s you, right ?
Since you’re here,
lend me your strength.
I wasn’t wrong about you.
You’re the third to enter here.
Senior,
is this thing
the person who followed you ?
Just a fragment of his Divine Sense
is enough to have an Ascendant cultivation.
After fighting him,
I temporarily trapped him in this formation.
As expected.
But the relation between Yunque Zi and Tuo Sen
seems to go beyond that.
It looks like
I still need to coax the truth out of him.
Wang Lin,
I’m gravely injured.
Could you get the Cultivation Planet Crystal for me ?
For my Forsaken Immortal Clan
and for you cultivators
the Cultivation Planet Crystal must not shatter !
Senior,
who that person ?
What is his relation with you ?
If you don't speak,
Junior will not approach.
Fine,
I guess I can tell you.
I just learned that
he is the one that orchestrated
the fall of planet Suzaku.
Thousands of years ago, my clan was driven underground.
I carried their hopes
and infiltrated the country of Suzaku
as Qian Pinghai’s disciple.
I trained relentlessly
to become the next Suzaku,
restore my clan’s freedom,
and escape the eternal darkness.
But I never imagined
that my Senior Brother would seize the position of Suzaku.
After thousands of years of waiting,
we ended up empty-handed.
Disillusioned with me,
Ancestor Xu abandoned hopes of peace
and activated the ancient altar
to seek for greater powers.
Little did we know,
beneath planet Suzaku
lies the corpse of an Ancient God.
A strand of his Divine Sense
answered our prayers
by helping Ancestor Xu to breakthrough
and shatter the first Suzaku's seal.
After that,
Ancestor Xu seemed to have gone mad
and he waged war on Suzaku.
I just realized that
this war
was just a part of that demon's scheme.
All of this
was a scheme to obtain the Cultivation Planet Crystal.
Tuo Sen’s scheme to try to get
the Cultivation Planet Crystal
can only mean only one thing.
It can free him from the Blood Sea.
If that is true,
I will not be able to escape him.
See for yourself with your Divine Sense.
I’m at my limit.
If he escapes,
he will take the crystal.
When that happens,
all hope will be lost...
If Senior is at his limit
then why is your cultivation
unexpectedly stable ?
How did you notice ?
That’s not the Cultivation Planet Crystal.
If you want this thing,
go ahead and take it.
You're worthy of being one of my 4 candidates.
You're right,
that isn't the Cultivation Planet Crystal.
That is only a shadow.
Touching it costs a high price
and reveals the location of the true crystal.
I promise you
that if you retrieve the crystal for me,
I’ll gift you my clan’s treasure.
Senior,
I want to learn how to use the straw hat
as a deposit.
Touch it.
I don’t want to kill you.
But if you refuse,
I won’t hold back.
You're my benefactor
so I'd rather not fight you.
I just want to get my soul strand back
and leave planet Suzaku
to pursue my own path.
But since Senior threatens to harm me now,
I'm pretty sure that if I touch this,
I will die for sure. Am I right ?
But your death
will allow me to repair the Cultivation Planet Crystal
and save countless lives !
That is a righteous act !
If you’re so righteous,
then teach me how to do it
and die a noble death.
Ridiculous !
Do you think your Soul Flag can match me ?
I’m no match for you.
But I know someone that is.
Little guy,
that formation was quite clever.
Using remnants of dead soul fragments as a formation
can indeed trap Master's Divine Sense.
However,
I must obtain the Cultivation Planet Crystal for Master.
And no one can stop me !
A mere puppet...
As long as I can destroy your Divine Sense,
no matter how strong your true body is,
you won’t be able to get here now !
Cultivation Planet Crystal
The Cultivation Planet Crystal !
The day Master will be free is before me !
Tuo Sen's Ascendant puppet was killed in an instant.
The Cultivation Planet Crystal really is deadly.
What !?
What is this place ?
Celestial Seal Pagoda\NInside the Cultivation Planet Crystal
Are you
willing to become
the titled Suzaku ?
To let go of the consequences of my actions
is to ignore the law of cause and effect
like scattered ink.
As destiny falls
in exchange for this moment of tainted dreams.
It makes the mountains lose their colors,
wither and melt into rivers.
Who can deceive
the law of the heavens ?
Countless generations
have tried before me.
But how could I not catch my dreams
within my warm fingers ?
You're at my side when I'm alone
giving me the strength to fight the will of the heavens.
Fortunately, my mind was open and honest.
I'm sorry we never got to see the fireworks
in the streets.
Can I break the vortex of our destiny ?
Can I break the rules ?
To run towards you !
I will fight the law of the heavens and the law of cause and effect
to cut down this tribulation with my own hands
and break through the reincarnation cycle.
All of that for the stars in your eyes.
I wish to bend this dream for the fire in my heart.
If your soul is willing to wander,
can I still take your hands
and hold them tight ?
I will defy the heavens and prevent the stars from falling.
I will overthrow the Immortals and the Demons in my heart.
I dream of destroying
the shackles of our fate.
You're the only one that can ignore the law of cause and effect.
You're the hardest to let go of.
I want to be with you again
so I can look in your eyes.
Even for a moment, it's worth it.